Finding Aid for German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora records, 1862-1895
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora records [microform] 1862-1895
German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora.
1 microfilm reel
851306 mf259c
German communal colony founded near Bay Port, Michigan by Emil Baur. Minutes, accounts, constitution, maps, and other related papers; also photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated in 1958 by Mrs. Robert E. Morse of Pigeon, Michigan (donor no. 3432 ). Additions were received in 1963.
The record group is open to research.
The originals of these records are located in the library. Researchers will normally be expected to use the microfilm edition
The German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora was a German communal colony founded near Bay Port, Michigan by Emil Baur.
The records of Ora Labora date from 1862 to 1895 and include minutes, accounts, constitution, maps, and other related papers. Some of the records are in German with some English translation.
Subjects:
Baur, Emil Gottlob, d. 1894.; Bay Port (Mich.); Cooperative societies--Michigan.; German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora.; German Americans--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bay Port (Mich.)--Collective settlements.; Collective settlements--Michigan--Bay Port.; German Americans--Organizations.; German Christian Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora.
Contributors:
Bauer, Emil Gottlob, d. 1894.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Society Records
  - Constitution, 1863 (Reel 1)
  - Undated history (Reel 1)
  - History by Lela Puffer (Reel 1)
  - Maps of colony lands (Reel 1)
  - Land certificates, 1860 and 1884 (Reel 1)
  - Letters, 1862-1938 (scattered dates) (Reel 1)
  - Authorization of settlement of society's affairs with Harmony Society, 1869 (Reel 1)
  - Typescript of report, 1862-1868 (English translation) (Reel 1)
  - Account sheet, 1866-1867 listing names of colonists, their shares, and their payment in goods (Reel 1)
  - Clippings
    - 1888-1893 (Reel 1)
    - 1926-1949 (Reel 1)
  - Miscellanea (Reel 1)
  - Photographs (copyprints); including portraits and view of the community (Reel 1)
  - Account book, 1864-1865, 1 volume (Reel 1)
  - Account book, 1866-1894, 1 volume (Reel 1)
  - Minute book, 1862-1868, 1 volume (Reel 1)
  - Account book-Minute book, 1 volume (Reel 1)
  - Account book, 1865-1895 (Reel 1)